<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<help>
	<function>mpt_demo_deployment_onlineMPC</function>
	
	<!-- one-line description of the function -->
	<info>
       Application of online MPC controller with the help of Simulink interface
	</info>
	
    <syntax>mpt_demo_deployment_onlineMPC</syntax>

	<!-- long description of the function -->
	<descr>
       Demonstration of real-time control using online MPC controller. 
       The demo relies on standalone LCP solver that solves the optimization
       problem given as linear-complementarity problem (LCP). 
       The LCP solver must be present in the installation path including the 
       extended version <bf>lcprtw</bf> that contains pre-compiled libraries
       for linking with OpenWatcom compiler. The demo has been tested under
       Real-Time Windows target and XPC target on Windows 32-bit platform.
       <br />       
       <bf>Note that this demo can be compiled and run on Windows 32-bit platform
       for Matlab r2012a!</bf> 
       <br />
        
        Deployment steps:
        <ol>
            <li> Generate the online controller that has the desired properties. </li>
            <li> Export the online controller to YALMIP using <tt>toYalmip</tt> method of <tt>MPCController</tt> class.</li>
            <li> Formulate a parametric optimization problem and specify the feedback variables that are used as parameters.</li>
            <li> Create an instance of <tt>Opt</tt> class and transform the optimization problem to LCP using <tt>qp2lcp</tt> method. </li>
            <li> Create a Simulink scheme with the S-Function block that links to LCP solver.</li>
            <li> In the Simulink scheme, choose code generation options and pick <bf>rtwin.tlc</bf> as the system target file 
            that corresponds to Real-Time Windows target or <bf>xpctarget.tlc</bf> for XPC target. </li>
            <li> Press "CTRL+B" that executes the code generation and compiles the code. </li>
            <li> In the Simulink scheme choose "Simulation-&gt;External" option and press "Connect To Target". </li>
            <li> Start the simulation to verify the controller in real-time. </li>
        </ol>
        
	</descr>    
    
	<!-- multiple related function can be defined -->
    <related>mpt_demo_deployment_explicitMPC</related>
	
	<!-- multiple authors can be defined -->
	<author macro="author_herceg"/>

	<!-- finally, the text of the license -->
	<license macro="GPL2"/>
</help>
