<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<help>
	<function>mptopt</function>
	
	<!-- one-line description of the function -->
	<info>
        Global option handler for MPT.
	</info>
	
	<syntax>mptopt('Parameter1',Value1,'Parameter2',Value2,...)</syntax>
    
	<!-- long description of the function -->
	<descr>
        The function/class <tt>mptopt</tt> plays the role of global option handler throughout MPT.
        Any specific option should be changed using <tt>mptopt</tt> function. The syntax follows
        the "parameter-value" scheme where the <tt>parameter</tt> is the desired option and <tt>value</tt>
        is the assignment to this option. The changes take effect immediatelly and are valid globally
        through the whole MPT toolbox. Global options are kept in memory after initialization and 
        any changes in the option are preserved between sessions.
        
	</descr>
	<!-- now describe input arguments -->
    <input>
        <name>Parameter1</name>
        <descr>The name of the desired option to be changed provided as string. The list of available options can be 
        obtained by typing <tt>properties('mptopt')</tt> at the Matlab prompt.</descr>
        <class name="char"/>
    </input>
    <input>
        <name>Value1</name>
        <descr>The value to be assigned to <tt>Parameter1</tt>. </descr>
        <class name="double or char"/>
    </input>
    <example>
        <descr>This example shows how to change LP solver to "CDD". </descr>
        <descr>To list which solvers are installed, invoke <tt>solvers_list</tt> option from <tt>mptopt</tt> class.</descr>
        <descr>This is achieved by assigning the output from <tt>mptopt</tt> class to some variable and referring to <tt>solvers_list</tt> field as follows:</descr>
        <cmd> s = mptopt </cmd>
        <cmd> s.solvers_list.LP </cmd>
        <descr> If CDD solver is present in the list, it means that it exist on the Matlab path. To change CDD solver as default for solving LP, it can be 
        done twofold. </descr>
        <descr> Assignment with the help of the output variable <tt>s</tt>:</descr>
        <cmd> s.lpsolver = 'CDD'; </cmd>
        <descr> or calling <tt>mptopt</tt> via standard syntax </descr>
        <cmd> mptopt('lpsolver','CDD'); </cmd>
    </example>
    <example>
        <descr>Options for any module are stored here as well. For instance, the geometry module of MPT that contains operations
        on polyhedra has the options stored under </descr>
        <cmd> s = mptopt; </cmd>
        <cmd> s.modules.geometry </cmd>
        <descr> These options can be changed from any instance of the script and take effect globally. To reset to default options
        use the function </descr>
        <cmd> mpt_init </cmd>
    </example>
	
	<!-- multiple related function can be defined -->
    <related>mpt_init</related>
	
	<!-- multiple authors can be defined -->
	<author macro="author_herceg"/>

	<!-- finally, the text of the license -->
	<license macro="GPL2"/>
</help>
